Xandice Armah

ADDRESS

East Sussex, Brighton BN1

xz-dice.github.io

xandicearmah+jobs@gmail.com

I am a well-motivated and organized developer with excellent communication skills.

I'm very willing to learn, quick to pick up new things and fully comfortable and capable of working under pressure and to a deadline. Over the past 6 years I have freelanced as a DJ in-between my full-time jobs and as well as cultivating a successful career, I have also been lucky enough to pick up a multitude of transferable skills.

I love **fixing things** and **troubleshooting** and wherever I go, on the road or in the office, I have always been the unofficial 'resident tech support' person, so learning **full-stack web development** feels like a natural progression.

EDUCATION

iO Academy

Full Stack Track

(March 2021 - June 2021)

I am currently studying remotely at iO Academy, a full-stack, intensive 16-week course where I am learning the fundamentals of programming. Over the past 4 months, I have acquired scrum master certification and worked remotely within a scrum team of 8 developers to produce several projects.

BA (Hons) Geography (September 2010 - July 2016)

University of Brighton

PROJECTS

Aptitude Test

https://github.com/xz-dice/aptitude-test

(May 2021 - May 2021)

This was a team project to add new frontend features and bug fixes within a legacy project. We used GULP as a taskrunner to compile our TypeScript and used Handlebars for JavaScript templating. As scrum master for this project, I supported team members and communicated with our partner team to ensure there were no conflicts between any stories with dependencies.

iO Academy Portal

https://github.com/xz-dice/AcademyPortal

(May 2021 - May 2021)

For this project we were required to add extra functionality to the iO Academy Portal, which is a legacy codebase. We used PHP, MVC, Slim and MySQL for the backend and data was displayed to the frontend using JavaScript and HTML.

Fetch https://github.com/iO-Academy/2021-march-fetch

(May 2021 - May 2021)

Fetch is an OOP PHP app which scrapes data from an API into a MySQL database and displays dogs so that you can get an idea of which dog is best for you. This project was managed in Scrum and we used Git for version control. We followed an agreed upon wireframe, used SOLID principles, and the hydrator design pattern to develop this app. This app's dependencies are managed by Composer and it was unit tested with PHPUnit.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance DJ & Co-Founder

Gal Pals

(September 2015 - Present)

- Organising, managing and promoting our regular club nights for approximately 400-600 attendees
- Lead on logistics, finance, booking venues and artists/performers
- Resident DJ, previously played at Glastonbury Festival, Primavera Sound, Brighton Dome and Brighton Pride.

Course Coordinator
University of Sussex

(April 2019 - February 2021)

- Dealing with student enquiries, maintaining assessment information, and supporting examination boards
- Coordinating support for a range of taught courses within the School
- Providing administrative support to members of faculty and to various school boards and meetings.

International Students Support Officer

University of Brighton

(July 2017 - November 2018)

- Co-ordinating the organisation of the international students' orientation programme
- Supporting the coordination of an ongoing programme of information, induction activities, social and cultural events primarily aimed at international and EU students.
- Providing pastoral support and advice for international and EU students.

President and Chair of the Board of Trustees

(July 2013 - June 2015)

Brighton Students' Union

- Elected and full-time representative providing leadership, working on strategic aims, and engaging and representing the needs of students at the University of Brighton at a local and national level.
- Chair of the Board of Trustees for Brighton Students' Union, a charity with a £2.7m turnover and 21,000 student members.

SKILLS

PHP
CSS Javascript
Git ReactJS
OOP MySQL
Node.js MongoDB
Express Pair Programming

CDD

MVC